Fairfield Collection
Fairfield Collection
- Alonzo C. Mather Papers
  - Inventions
    - Humane stock car
      - Legal material, 12 items (Box 11)
      - Printed material
        - Advertising material, 48 items (Box 12)
        - American Humane Association, 1880; 1881; 2 items (Box 12)
        - Humane Journal clippings, 12 items (Box 12)
      - Records
        - "List of Newspapers and Public Men sent Circulars - To Stock Transportation Co.", 1 item (Box 12)
        - Reports of patent and common cars, 1 item (Box 12)
        - Stockyard logs, 1923; 12 items (Box 12)
      - Scrapbook, 1 item (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous, 5 items (Box 12)
    - Patents
      - Airplane
        - German patent, 1912; 8 items (Box 12)
        - Notes and sketches, 21 items (Box 12)
      - Pneumatic spring, 1894; 3 items (Box 13)
      - Railroad track, 1894; 2 items (Box 13)
      - Self-lacing boot and glove
        - Documents, 1883-1886; 11 items (Box 13)
        - Patents, 1883-1884; 13 items in 2 folders (Box 13)
        - Patent, England, 1883
      - Unidentified patent drawings, 8 items (Box 13)
    - Power bridge and water-regulating devices
      includes material relating to Mather's proposed bridge to generate electricity from Niagara Falls, as well as related power-generating technologies
      - Blueprints and patents, 10 items (Box 13)
      - Correspondence
        - A-W, 1900-1907; 23 items (Box 13)
        - André Citroën and Company, 1908; 3 items (Box 13)
        - Brill, George M., 1904-1905; 5 items (Box 13)
        - Chains, 1904-1905; 18 items (Box 13)
        - Churchyard, Joseph J., 1905; 8 items (Box 13)
        - Corliss, Hon. John B., 1900-1903; Representative for proposing the bridge; 19 items (Box 13)
        - Cowper, T. D., 1893-1900; 18 items (Box 13)
        - Dean, Cyrus S., 1906-1907; 23 items (Box 14)
        - Decker, Arthur W., 1901; 10 items (Box 14)
        - Levin, A. M., 1905-1906; 15 items (Box 14)
        - Lockwood, Stephen T., 1896-1900; 10 items (Box 14)
        - Norris, James L., 1899-1902; patent lawyer; 8 items (Box 14)
        - O'Keefe and Orbison, 1904-1905; 20 items (Box 14)
        - "Responses to bids for hydraulic cylinders", 1905; 24 items (Box 14)
        - Wisner, Geo. Y., 1903; 4 items (Box 14)
        - Outgoing correspondence, 8 items (Box 14)
      - Legislative material, 1891; 1893-1900,; 1902,; undated; 30 items (Box 14)
      - Photographs, 8 items (Box 14)
      - "Plan for power house", 14 items (Box 14)
      - Printed material
        - Advertising material, 5 items (Box 14)
        - Clippings
          - International Waterways Commission, 1905; 12 items (Box 14)
          - Mather Power Bridge, 1895-1900; 1906; 29 items (Box 14)
          - Niagara power, 1889-1895; 17 items (Box 14)
  - Memorabilia
    - Address book, 1 items (Box 15)
    - Clippings
      - Airplanes, 1918; undated; includes correspondence regarding suggestions for improvements; 20 items (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous, 1890-1902; 4 items (Box 15)
    - Notes and sketches, 50 items (Box 15)
    - Photograph of Alonzo C. Mather, 1888; 1 items (Box 15)
    - Writings, 2 items (Box 15)
  - Professional interests
    - Brewster sanitarium, a project by Dr. Flora A. Brewster to build a sanitarium, which Mather aided financially
      - Correspondence, 1899-1905; primarily between Brewster and Mather; 114 items in 3 folders (Box 15)
      - Documents, 8 items (Box 15)
    - Buffalo, New York
      - The Alliance, 1900-1909; apartment building financed by Mather; 31 items (Box 15)
      - "House memo", 5 items (Box 15)
      - Real estate, 1895; 5 items (Box 15)
      - Reciprocity League
        Organization dedicated to promoting free trade
        - Correspondence, 1898; 1902-1905; primarily with Campbell Shaw, secretary of the Lower Lakes Reciprocity League (of which Mather was vice president); 21 items (Box 15)
        - Clippings, 1903; 11 items (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 13 items (Box 15)
- Albert B. Watkins Papers
  - Correspondence
    - Family, 1867-1880; undated; 26 items (Box 16)
    - General
      - A-Y, 1863-1870; undated; 89 items in 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Unidentified, 3 items (Box 16)
    - Personal
      - B-Y, 1863-1869; undated; 32 items (Box 16)
      - Babbitt, Jas. H., 1863-1867; 17 items (Box 16)
      - Baldwin, R. S., 1863-1865; 4 items (Box 16)
      - Cutting, Chas. (Charles), 1863-1868; 14 items (Box 16)
      - Henderson, J. D., 1865-1867; 5 items (Box 16)
      - Leggett, C. D., 1867-1870; undated; 6 items (Box 16)
      - Merrill, George R., 1863-1867; undated; 17 items (Box 17)
      - Morrill, G. W. (George Willard), 1863-1866; undated; 5 items (Box 17)
      - Quinby, J. W., 1864-1870; 11 items (Box 17)
      - Randall, —, 1864; undated; 5 items (Box 17)
      - Ward, John, 1863-1869; undated; 20 items (Box 17)
      - Wells, George H. (Huntington), undated; 5 items (Box 17)
  - Documents, 1863-1880; undated; 25 items (Box 17)
- Miscellaneous
  - Unidentified correspondence and fragments, 1836-1898; undated; 13 items (Box 17)
  - Unsigned manuscripts, 19 items (Box 17)
  - Printed material, 35 items (Box 17)
  - "Transcripts from Colonial Record", 1897; relates to Edward Griswold (1607-1691), of whom Sarah Buell (née Griswold) (1769-1856) is a descendent; 1 item (Box 17)